Guide to the Helen Martha Wright Papers 1774-1969 MS 3111
New-York Historical Society
Helen Martha Wright papers
1774-1969
New-York Historical Society
Wright, Helen Martha
MS 3111
12 Linear feet in 10 cartons, one flat box, and one oversize folder
This collection consists mainly of Wright's genealogical research notes organized by subject, as well as some of her personal papers including photographs and correspondence. Of special interest are Civil War era diaries and correspondence in the Connett Family files.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers. Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Biographical / Historical
Helen Martha Wright (1884-1969) was an historian, genealogist, and teacher from New Jersey.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
No information is available at this time.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by subject.
Related Materials
The New-York Historical's Patricia D. Klingenstein Library holds a number of volumes written by Helen Martha Wright.
Cartes-de-visite (card photographs); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Indentures.; Research notes.; Genealogy.; Women historians -- United States.; New Jersey -- Genealogy.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Correspondence.
- Helen Martha Wright personal papers, 1930-1969 (Offsite-box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Contains photos, notes, correspondence.
- Helen Martha Wright personal papers, 1930-1969 (Offsite-box 2)
- Helen Martha Wright books, 1810-1920 (Offsite-box 11)
  Contains books from Wright's personal library.
- Connett family papers, 1800-1952 (Offsite-box 3)
  Connett family photos, diaries, correspondence. Includes material from Cornelia Connett, Clara Connett Wright, Belinda Connett, Will Thompson. The correspondence is mostly to and from Will Thompson, a Union soldier in a New Jersey brigade. The diaries were kept by Cornelia Connett and her daughter, Clara Connett Wright.
- Connett family papers, 1800-1952 (Offsite-box 4)
- Connett family research, 1965-1968 (Offsite-box 5)
- De Haven family research, 1930-1968 (Offsite-box 6)
- De Haven family research, 1935-1969 (Offsite-box 7)
- De Haven family scrapbook, 1930-1968 (Offsite-box 10)
- Dean family research, 1930-1969 (Offsite-box 8)
- Doty family research, 1935-1968 (Offsite-box 9)
- Fairchild family research, 1935-1968 (Offsite-box 8)
- Haupt family research, 1935-1969 (Offsite-box 7)
- Indentures, 1774-1846 (Case OS Medium)
  Contains handwritten deeds for properties in Pennsylvania.